<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-03T23:18:29+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Making Sense</title><subtitle>This blog aims to reconcile, organize, and share my thoughts. Feel free to email feedback.</subtitle><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><entry><title type="html">Meaningful Values</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/real-time-philosophy/2018/11/03/Meaningful-Value.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meaningful Values" /><published>2018-11-03T23:12:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T23:12:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/real-time-philosophy/2018/11/03/Meaningful-Value</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/real-time-philosophy/2018/11/03/Meaningful-Value.html">&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for something to be meaningful? We rarely stop and ponder what it truly means; &lt;em&gt;getting into this college is meaningful to me&lt;/em&gt;—but &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;em&gt;Maintaining this relationship is meaningful to us&lt;/em&gt;—but &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;? Dismissing “&lt;em&gt;meaning”&lt;/em&gt; as some inferior, emotional concept is simple enough, but doesn’t provide any practical advice. And still, since we are, regrettably, humans with monkey brains, emotions exists and is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few moments of consideration leads to the unavoidable question: Why does anything matter if we are going to die anyways? Everything we hold value to will meet an end—from the point of your death, nothing would matter anymore. (Note, though, that this is equally true when death is eliminated; if we live forever, why would doing anything matter? We have (literally) all the time in the world.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I formed a personal attachment to the concept because I found “happiness” an unsatisfactory answer to the question: &lt;em&gt;what is the meaning of life?&lt;/em&gt; Emotions like joy and happiness are easily manipulated and tricked, ultimately unstable, and therefore should not form a basis for questions as important as the purpose of conscious life. Regressing to a higher level and asking back: “What is &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; anyways?”, was my solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, defining &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; as “extracting positive emotions,” would be circular, which quickly eliminates any arguments regarding the &lt;em&gt;biological&lt;/em&gt; purpose of life. Referencing a dictionary: &lt;em&gt;“important or worthwhile quality; purpose: this can lead to new meaning in the life of older people,”&lt;/em&gt; we can redefine &lt;em&gt;meaningfulness&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; of life; the &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; of love—the only difference being that &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; has a more personal nuance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Value, though, is different from &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt;. Value includes the process—the effort and work, the tools and techniques—to achieve a &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt;. In a sense, the &lt;em&gt;goal&lt;/em&gt; is what the outside world sees. Value, though, is personal. The goal in an exam is to get a good score, but the value, could be something like “testing one’s understanding.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Value, though, is equally vague in its origins, and faces the same problem with rational reasons: &lt;em&gt;why is anything valuable if we die&lt;/em&gt;; and emotional approaches: &lt;em&gt;recreational drugs make you happy—so are they valuable?&lt;/em&gt; What we want might be a mixture of emotional and rationality—something that links those two together, but not in a way where logic maps, or &lt;em&gt;manipulates&lt;/em&gt; emotion, rather where &lt;em&gt;emotion&lt;/em&gt; governs our reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is quite natural for us. We develop tools and techniques to be more productive, to reduce our workload, to be less tired. We use our skills, or &lt;em&gt;reasoning capabilities,&lt;/em&gt; in order to make money, to buy things that make us happy. Or maybe making money naturally brings you happiness. In any case, value is derived from reasoning, but ultimately concludes with emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s simply our desire to hide from the outside world the fact that we are, ultimately, emotional creatures. Feelings cannot be clearly communicated—but rational reasons can. While the world does not consider your own feelings, you and your family, friends, might. But you cannot simply go into a job interview and proudly declare “I applied just to make money,” and you equally cannot say “My sole reason for this relationship is to maximize personal happiness.” &lt;em&gt;Meaning&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; would, then, ultimately be a conflict between the outside world and our inner minds—the clash between &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;emotion,&lt;/em&gt; the discrepancy between what we think and what we feel, wrapped up in one simple and convenient word. It isn’t something to be embarrassed about to say out loud, but it certainly is a thought-provoking concept.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">What does it mean for something to be meaningful? We rarely stop and ponder what it truly means; getting into this college is meaningful to me—but why? Maintaining this relationship is meaningful to us—but why? Dismissing “meaning” as some inferior, emotional concept is simple enough, but doesn’t provide any practical advice. And still, since we are, regrettably, humans with monkey brains, emotions exists and is inevitable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Air Support</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Air Support" /><published>2018-08-07T18:04:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T18:04:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support.html">&lt;p&gt;In response to a Q&amp;amp;A session with Stephen Wolfram after my summer camp, I found a particular one of his answers interesting. The question he was asked was about his personal reconciliation of the discrepancies; the academic “purity” of his work—contemplating on the extents of physics, while also running a multi-national, for-profit firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer was: he doesn’t. The interesting part, though, was how he described the interaction between these two categories—foundational and applied—as “air support,” as concepts devised in one are applicable on the other. This pragmatic view aligned with how I naturally seemed to perceive my own problems as well—practicing math often gives insight into social problems, algorithms for solving purely academic problems apply to real-world ones, and trivial gossip at school can leave deep insight into some interesting branches of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this imply? The principle of emergence—or as Stephen Wolfram would describe it, computational equivalence—dictates the arising complexity of applied fields. But the more fundamental subjects are abstracted far beyond what these simple connections would imply—how this “air support” apparently works. I hope to talk about this in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">In response to a Q&amp;amp;A session with Stephen Wolfram after my summer camp, I found a particular one of his answers interesting. The question he was asked was about his personal reconciliation of the discrepancies; the academic “purity” of his work—contemplating on the extents of physics, while also running a multi-national, for-profit firm.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Probability</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Probability" /><published>2018-08-01T21:28:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T21:28:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability.html">&lt;p&gt;A major shift in my perspective of how I should lead life began with considering the following prayer, by Reinhold Niebuhr (1892-1971):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;God grant me the serenity
to accept the things I cannot change; 
courage to change the things I can; 
and wisdom to know the difference.
(…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am often blinded by a false, but tempting notion that there is a way of doing that is better;  that there is always another path that will reward a better life. This idea was rooted in me by a quote from Rob Siltanen, renowned for its adoption in Apple’s “Think Different” ad campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Here’s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers. The round pegs in the square holes. The ones who see things differently. They’re not fond of rules. And they have no respect for the status quo. You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them. About the only thing you can’t do is ignore them. Because they change things. They push the human race forward. And while some may see them as the crazy ones, we see genius. Because the people who are crazy enough to think they can change the world, are the ones who do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both, at a glance equally meaningful quotes, and do seem to hold some truths. But neither can coexist, they are mutually exclusive mindsets—to accept the status quo, or to reject it. Yet either are both tempting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of my Theory of Knowledge classes, we were offered some situations and were to predict using inductive logic—e.g. the likelihood of a stock price to rise or fall, either without context, or given that it has been rising steadily the last 10 years. Smugly, I proceeded to reject all evidence and only stick to what is knowable, answering that neither is more likely in all contexts. I was surprised to find that I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a limit to understanding a perspective, to what is feasibly knowable. There is no ideal perfect information in markets, or the ability to foretell the existence of black swans before it is discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who shout life is unfair, do not consider the intrinsic randomness that life offers fairly to everyone. There is cause and effect and to an extent predictability, but those processes are so minuscule and microscopic that it is infeasible to try to understand. Balancing this unfairness, luck, and unpredictability, the simplest way to sum this up is to consider life as a sequence of probabilistic events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that there are too many unpredictable variables, the only choice is to stick to the things we know. We look at what we have, make estimates, and choose the path that is most likely to lead to our desired future. All we can do is to increase the number of variables we have, and learn how to interpret them more correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, if life is led by probability, not certainty or emotion, it is necessary to look after and console ourselves, and hope that our minds have the emotional strength to cope with our choices, and to take responsibility, may the result be favorable or not, the serenity, to accept the things I cannot change; courage, to change the things I can; and wisdom, to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">A major shift in my perspective of how I should lead life began with considering the following prayer, by Reinhold Niebuhr (1892-1971):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual Reality</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual Reality" /><published>2018-07-25T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality.html">&lt;p&gt;My vision with computer science starts with, rather anti-climactically, with a children’s book about Chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the famous “Why?” Book-length cartoon series in Korea, the story introduced difficult chemistry concepts in a digestible children’s book. The writers, in an attempt to make the book realistic and easier to plot, set the characters in a virtual reality game, where the laws of physics, (and ironically chemistry as well) could easily be bent to facilitate explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learn more, academically, socially (or in that matter in any sense), I keep reiterating back to this imaginary world. The world, as it turns out to a depressed 8th-grader, was not a nice, cozy, neat, organized place designed for me and my friends, but a messy competition, blinded and handicapped, with the sole thread of knowledge and probability, to hang on to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was, as I observed, not out of intension, but out of inevitability. More people strive to be better, either out of pure selflessness or a selfish desire of self-worth. Immorality, as I view it, is a result of the flaws in the system designed to handle these interactions. These systems are inevitably built upon a physical foundation, constrained by the laws of physics, and requires heavy maintenance. Meetings need to be scheduled according to time zones, conversations cannot continue with people in different circadian rhythms, a romantic date will likely fail without a beautiful restaurant or on other sides of the world. Economies are strung by the rapid development of technology and more recently, intellectual automation, and are failing to transparently expose or fix the problems with economic crises, or the near-future result of massive unemployment, or more personally, inflation of academic or experience requirements, without it being anyone’s fault but the system’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I do see hope in many cases. The open source initiative, where programmers are voluntarily helping to develop complex programs, a community like reddit withstanding being plagued by the normal problems of social services, and the fact that these organizations and systems are capable of sustaining themselves, project a faraway, but hopeful future, where the best of humanity’s traits can shine. A technological utopia, where logistical problems are a thing of the past, and ideas and relationships can flow and prosper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems we see now, are remnants of the inevitable system of the past—just like the first books that emerged decades after the printing press was invented, we are not yet taking advantage of the accelerating technological advances of the last decade. But we do see some, advancing into and building this future, such as blockchain, machine learning, and virtual reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a virtual universe, a world can be built from scratch. A new economic system can be tested simply with a change of code, or time zones can be eliminated, or rather, will not exist in the first place. Physical distance doesn’t mean anything anymore—people can be teleported, or with a more intuitive user interface where one may just be able to think to move—or fly, or swim, or perform any other means of movement they desire. If we can parse thought, why, then, limit ourselves to our primitive bodies designed for survival? A virtualized projection of oneself can take any form, one can choose to be any animal, a robot, or anything that suits their desires—but there will be always some who choose to remain in our human forms. New forms of communication will form, and nobody will be far away from anybody else. Most problems of the world, at the very least, the physical ones, will be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, of course, a far-fetched daydream. The logistics of getting us into this future, will be hindered more by economics and finance than technology. Then after by ethics, and philosophy and psychology and sociology. And then there are the practical problems in implementing the code—who designs how the world should work? Massive, multiple year-long public debates need to take place on designing and publishing the work, and when an opposition team decides to fork the brach and start a new world with different rules, the project itself will lose its purpose, as the self-aware users, us, are what ultimately gives any universe meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pleasant thought experiment for most, but for me, it is life-long dream. When I code, contribute to an open-source initiative, or experiment with hosting my website; when I learn a new concept in economics, thinking about how this system could be generalized and implemented if there were no physical hinderance—above a certain abstraction, or more likely anything abstracted upon the natural sciences—sociology, psychology, economics, history—are subject to this consideration—how will this work without rules? If we could make this better, why? It is not only a useful mental model, but a consideration of the pure mechanics of the subject—the reason this subject exists, and is studied by humanity’s greatest minds. And it frees us from the practical consideration—if a new idea emerges, one no longer has to dismiss it as impractical or infeasible to replace, but can develop it further. Ideas will no longer be judged by its physical viability, but by its intrinsic value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connected world that we live in is currently a reflected version of our real world—the familiar desktop interface, the mouse, the “web,” or even the word “web-site” merely represents a physical object. When we are willing to detach from this physical world, however, those metaphors can become real, no longer reflections. We will, then finally, drop the word virtual, and live in our own versions of reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">My vision with computer science starts with, rather anti-climactically, with a children’s book about Chemistry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning of the End</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning of the End" /><published>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html">&lt;p&gt;Each experience in life can be lamented as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: a unique and exciting gift, but also a curse, due to the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, regret becomes, on some level, the boundary between these two sides: the more things you consider part of a general whole, the less regret you have, but the less preciseness you feel. The fact that &lt;em&gt;“The sun will rise tomorrow”&lt;/em&gt; instills hope and therefore implies a lack of regret, but as a consequence each day is stripped of its significance. On the other hand if one was to obsess on the unique weather of each day, then they would be astonished and amazed every day simply staring up at the sky, but would be full of disappointment that it will soon be gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common Japanese phrase: &lt;em&gt;“when you start hoping for this moment thing to last, it is the beginning of the end.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">Each experience in life can be lamented as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: a unique and exciting gift, but also a curse, due to the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should like studying</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should like studying" /><published>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html">&lt;p&gt;Not many classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but the work itself—is an abnormality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A necessary detail is that my school is not subject to problems plaguing some high schools—our teachers are passionate, insightful, and never decline a request for help. There are no serious social issues, and especially since the school is so small, everyone is part of a tightly-knit group. So some of my observation and experiences might be limited to my own school, and I do not deny that many of these insights are only obtainable in a well-maintained education system. But I still do argue that this is how one should approach learning, regardless of their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should not consider studying as work per se. In my “Why Be Productive” essay, I discussed the subtle distinctions between contribution and maintenance. Studying, at a high school level, is preparation for such contributions. You are given, through education, the building blocks with which you can create and contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be why many might indeed feel that what they are learning is “useless.” Maintenance does not require abstract or critical thinking skills—a part-time cashier will benefit nothing from their calculus class, as well as most white-collar workers. The real meaning of studying these subjects are in that they provide the ingredients for thinking—an insight into a particular school of thought. Such flexible resoning skills are required in almost all but the most physical labor—which are now mostly automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a more idealistic point of view, these ingredients will work to contribute, and the goal of higher level would be to push the human race forward, in the hopes that everyone capable would be creating and advancing civilization each moment. Like the term “Liberal Arts” that imply the necessity of education, in that one is imprisoned by the lack of knowledge, education, ideally, is the necessary process that puts everyone at the level in which they have the choice to create, whether they take the path or not. I would be willing to argue that is is &lt;em&gt;immoral&lt;/em&gt; not to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, though, studying is unavoidable to fair well in life. Especially in my culture, good grades do decide a major portion of life—even as much as luck. I cannot deny such a fear is also a subconscious motivation for me “liking” studying—but I do try to enjoy it as much as possible. A major personal paradigm shift in my viewpoint was when I took an advanced physics courses during the end of 8th grade. Learning up to a point where you are told that this is the forefront of this subject—and especially when that subject is one that aims to describe how this universe operates, shows, &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;, that there are no insurmountable mountains of knowledge, that there is an end to every subject; and &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt;, a picture of myself advancing into these further uncharted territories. Confidence, and curiosity, is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this paradigm, each subject reveals its own appeal. Physics gives you the foundations for your world view (one potential, fundamental truth), and states that you, as well as everything else in the universe are, are twelve particles interacting in specific ways. Chemistry describes how these particles come together to form an atom, and again how they come together to interact in interesting ways. Biology, leading somewhat to our own bias towards ourselves, specializes in how these interactions make up living things, while Neuroscience further specializes in the brain. Psychology describes how a brain might behave, and Sociology describes how a bunch of brains can come together to form patterns and regulations in behavior. Economics, or Political science has an additional layer of artificial separation—capitalism, and democracy, communism, etc.—whose ideas we actually live in.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most students, I believe, may stand on the top of this mountainous stack, but have no knowledge of what they stand upon. I still do not understand each piece of this mountain that I am standing on, and nobody will ever. However, what I do know is the system with which this monument of human knowledge is built upon, the protocols in which new blocks are added, and a vague grasp of each major structural part. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt;, is what makes studying interesting for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Math and Computer Science, though, is different. I hope to address that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">Not many classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but the work itself—is an abnormality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Be Productive?</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Be Productive?" /><published>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html">&lt;p&gt;The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, &lt;em&gt;work is nobody’s favorite subject.&lt;/em&gt; Yet, I find such systems deeply interesting, often diving deeper than what would be practical. The beginning of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained an admiration of this art of &lt;em&gt;self-discipline&lt;/em&gt;, as I often do with this kind of topic. I hope to reveal my personal reason for this choice, and outline a few techniques that I actually implement, hoping that it might help anybody who needs it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for wasting time on unnecessarily deep investigations on increasing efficiency (like this essay) is to maximize &lt;em&gt;future freedom&lt;/em&gt;. My studies should not prevent me from occasionally wanting to stay in bed until noon, or spontaneously taking a long walk on a weekday evening. Discipline, therefore, would be equivalent to buying time for your future self; a way of allowing them to focus on what they—my future self—&lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;, rather than what I want right now. I sometimes imagine a device that can save and restore time at will—for example, you could save an hour of commute time and be unconscious during that interval, and later use it when necessary, stopping the world around you. Being productive is the closest to this fantasy, as the problem of time management is procrastination, not a lack of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we were to suppose a device to control time, it it might also be practical to imagine that similar technologies would have freed us from labor. In an ideal world, nobody would be required to work. Despite notions that work allows us to “contribute to society,” or “give back what you got,” actuallly meaningful contributions to our world is driven not by financial need, like work, but rather by passion. People who find meaning in creating—artists, musicians, developers—would continue to produce work regardless of whether they get something in return or not. Most current jobs can and will be automated in the near future, and are far from contributions, closer to maintenance. Critical roles in our current world—government branches, financial institutions—are simply jobs that lubricate the gears that turn the wheels of society, and despite the importance and indispensability of such work in contemporary society, they do not offer true advancements to our race. Most contemporary work is subject to simple or complex physical mechanization, and as intellectual automation gets affordable and reliable, most jobs—including those that are crucial in our current understanding of society—would become meaningless. Mental and physical freedom from labor is, therefore, the end goal of increasing productivity. The ultimate objective isn’t to balance work, but rather to remove it.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is meaningful work, then? This closely relates to my interpretation of freedom—when one is free to do whatever they want, then some small portion would choose to create. Creativity in not only the arts, but in all academic disciplines, increasing the database of human knowledge, and trying to make better sense of our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will skip discussions of such an ideal world, though, to return to more practical advice. The key to efficiency is to reducing the overhead in every task. This includes automating repetitive and dull tasks if possible (easier in computational tasks than physical ones), e.g. stockpiling supplies or scripting workflows. Simplicity is crucial in maintaining efficiency, as our minds are not well-equipped for complexity greater than a certain threshold. This is not to be confused with visual complexity—a clean room can be efficient, but a dirty room in which its owner can easily locate everything is equally economical. If something, whether it be an idea, project, or an object, is unnecessary, throw it out. If it isn’t, organize it in within your own system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organization systems can be a bit more flexible, as knowing what works for you is more important than following a certain principle. I personally use a system called Getting Things Done&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, accompanied by program called Omnifocus, in which I collect any ideas or due tasks, which are then formatted and organized into subsections &lt;em&gt;called&lt;/em&gt; Projects. Other features are minor conveniences, but the crucial part of any program, or even a paper-based system is the ability to capture every drifting idea, a passing thought, and then to organize and display them when needed. For example, if I were to think of a topic for a blog post, the task manager would be responsible for recording what I tell it about my thought, organizing it into the right projects (giving enough information), and displaying it when I sit down to write. This process is rather a popular one, and is outlined in a short and informative video from CrashCourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One must, however, be aware of the time cost for managing this system, relative to the cost of actually executing each task. This problem is a common and well documented occurrence&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Another trap that can be more subtle, but equally dangerous, is that of endless self-improvement. That is, internalizing barriers in tasks, rather than identifying and addressing an external issue. An article about a more generalized version of this problem can be found here&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Be careful also to be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a task costs less than a threshold (e.g. 5 minutes), do it immediately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A self-aware disciplinary task accomplished first in the morning effectively increases motivation for the rest of the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing productivity can be a rewarding and interesting experience, given that one avoids the common pitfalls and misconceptions. I am still in the midst of continually altering and experimenting with my system of organization, and I do not see my journey ending quite soon yet, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; CGPGrey. Humans Need Not Apply. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; “Jony Ive Debuts iOS 7: ‘Bringing Order To Complexity’”. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; techcrunch.com/2013/06/11/jony-ives-debutes-ios-7-bringing-order-to-complexity/. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Crash Course Efficiency &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; XKCD. Efficiency. https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/efficiency.png. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Improving Ourselves to Death. https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/01/15/improving-ourselves-to-death. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, work is nobody’s favorite subject. Yet, I find such systems deeply interesting, often diving deeper than what would be practical. The beginning of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained an admiration of this art of self-discipline, as I often do with this kind of topic. I hope to reveal my personal reason for this choice, and outline a few techniques that I actually implement, hoping that it might help anybody who needs it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Math and Computer Science</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Math and Computer Science" /><published>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was part of an essay for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of mathematics, I believe, is what describes the very nature of who we are — inevitably, though, as the world itself, in my understanding, may be just a complex execution of a mathematical program. Zooming out, however, cryptography and number theory, but more so mathematics in general, are both subjects of my greatest passion, in their practical application, but more so in their elegance and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was an elementary school student in Korea, I was recommended a book called “The Mathematics Shop,” which told the stories of Pythagoras’s theorem, Euclidian geometry, or &lt;em&gt;Gauss’s Seven Bridges of Königsberg&lt;/em&gt; with pictures and stories. For me, the book contained, more than anything, stories that told me how our world is designed—maths is a story playing in the theatre that is our world, our universe. It engraved, in my young mind, a principle that I would later discover to be the base of my personality: that our universe is fundamentally a mathematical one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very personal but quite common first encounter with number theory, for me, was with Goldbach’s conjecture. Another mathematics book recommended to me by my middle school Korean math teacher told a fictional story about a mathematician attempting, though failing, to prove the conjecture. For a Korean 7th-grade student, math was something to despise and hate, as a subject that brings down your grades. This book broke this overshadowing perception that mathematics is a problem-solving subject—that practicing mathematics is much different from learning it, and more importantly, that it is a &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; subject, requiring creativity as much as insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I researched for more information on these fields, but soon realized that without formal education my understanding was limited. I asked my teachers for recommendations, who pointed me to summer courses at nearby schools, in which I took courses in basic discrete mathematics, number theory, and combinatorics. The foundations of these subjects help me through my current courses, but more importantly, helped me realize early on what I was “missing out on.” There were whole worlds of mathematics that were to be explored, that I have never seen before. This was when I saw how deep this field can go, and how naïve I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, through its connection with my interest in computer science, I discovered how interesting the field of cryptography can be, on a mathematical level. My math research project assessment in my first year of IB, was a chance to show my interests in these fields, and I chose my topic in cryptography: a mathematical analysis of an encryption device, the Enigma machine. In the abstract of the research paper in which I discussed the encryption mechanisms of the device as well as how it was broken, I expressed the reason for my choice of topic, that I would like to &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption.html&quot;&gt;share&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now pursuing mathematics in my IB Mathematics Higher Level course, while also preparing for AP Calculus exam in May. The knowledge I gain from these courses, however, as I see now, are merely tools in practicing mathematics. I am now only halfway—or even less—done climbing to the figurative shoulders of giants; what I might me able to witness at the top of them, how much more of the world I can make sense, is what excites me to try every new opportunity to learn math.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This was part of an essay for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp" /><published>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This report can also be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stmaur.ac.jp/news/science/three-days-ysfh-science-immersion-camp&quot;&gt;school website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my interest in science, I have always fulfilled my scientific curiosity in solitude; most of my friends did not have as deep a level of appreciation towards the subject as I did, and my teachers had priorities of teaching everyone altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say, however, that I did not consider science as a fundamentally collaborative  activity. I am aware most research or studies are done as a team, and even if a person works alone, they would not get too far without advice, or any previous work. As Newton once said, “I am standing on the shoulders of giants;” it is just that I haven’t done really exciting, collaborative, science before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the experience during the Science Immersion Camp was quite new to me. First, there was the fact that this was school mainly taught in Japanese; I was unfamiliar with the Japanese school culture, and I initially had a hard time communicating with my buddy. One particular thing, however, that we both were interest in, was physics; he was planning to take the subject next year, and I was thrilled to find somebody that was genuinely interested in it—not as an academic subject, but as a true interest. I was able to break the ice with some physics discussion, and also got comfortable with my group members during the process. I was surprised to meet a person in my age group that all shared the same excitement towards science, and that talking about it was considered a natural conversational topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, was the classes. Though I am lucky to study in a school equipped with various scientific equipments, I have to admit, the facilities in the Science Frontier High school was more advanced. The majority of the classes I took was in the labs, and with practical experiments—many that I only learned in theory. It was fascinating to see results that matched the theories that I had learned. I especially enjoyed the astronomy class, during which we calculated the age of the universe using Hubble’s constant, calculated by spectral data collected from real observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the closing assembly, one of the guest teachers said that the basis for scientific research is communication, and more and more of that is done in English. I was lucky to participate in this camp which not only taught me, but let me experience those words myself, and shifted my view on how science is done—with communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This report can also be found on my school website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on Encryption</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on Encryption" /><published>2017-09-05T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an extract from the rationale of my research on the Enigma Machine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encryption is a crucial part of our lives in this age of information. For all practical purposes, though, encryption may seem to be unneeded; Assuming everybody is well-purposed and are “nice” people, there is no reason to hide information. However, by nature humans desire privacy, and that desire is one of the fundamental principles of our complicated modern society. Whether it is to keep military secrets, or to hide your embarrassing texts with your ex-boyfriend, encryption, I believe, represents a technology solely developed for humans. Our craving for privacy and secrecy is what defines our unique identity, and encryption is what enables us to do so in the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another significant fact about the Engima machine is that it was defeated. The fact that the first encryption device, thought to be unbreakable, was broken, reveals how every encryption method is capable of being exploited, and the designer should always keep that fact in mind. Modern encryption methods, however complicated, is theoretically breakable; the currently widely-used RSA algorithms can be defeated using a quantum algorithm; and there have already been advances in replacement technologies for when quantum computing would become mainstream. This shows the basic incompleteness of encryption, and that there is no “perfect” method, only a better one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By understanding the mathematics behind the Enigma and the Bombe, I believe I would gain a better understanding of the fundamental ideas behind encryption; how, but more importantly, why, we design encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/Enigma/index.html&quot;&gt;full research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This is an extract from the rationale of my research on the Enigma Machine.</summary></entry></feed>