<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-22T13:22:47+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/</id><title type="html">Making Sense</title><subtitle>This blog aims to reconcile, organize, and share my thoughts. Feel free to email feedback.</subtitle><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Reason I use Apple Products</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/22/Apple.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reason I use Apple Products" /><published>2018-08-22T13:16:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-08-22T13:16:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/22/Apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/22/Apple.html">&lt;p&gt;Apple may be one of, possibly the most controversial tech company in existence, at least among those who care. So there must be a reason why I self-identify as a proud user of Apple products. I own a MacBook Pro that is 4 years old now, an iPhone 5 and iPhone 6S, and frequent our family’s iPad Pro for my drawings with the overpriced Apple Pencil. I also recently purchased my AirPods which I, despite its admittedly awkward looks, treasure. On top of that, all of my accessories, including cases, adapters, and chargers, are all Apple-branded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not completely sure or even aware of this phenomenon until recently, but a realization revealed that I happen to like their corporate philosophy, much more that I like their products. Of course, the politically correct opinion would be that “every brand has its advantages and drawbacks,” and “choosing the right tool” is much more important than who made it. But in this post, rather controversially, I would like to challenge that claim, and give a few reasons why I, personally, consider Apple products to be undoubtedly superior in most use cases, as well as my own speculation in why the company chooses to design in such a way. Most of the argument would be macOS and iOS, Apple’s desktop and mobile operating systems, respectively, against Windows and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most prominent advantage of being an Apple user is the consistency of its products. The app ecosystem for both macOS and iOS, as well as the behavior of most programs, are vastly more consistent and well-thought that their Windows and Android counterparts. The preferences menu, in most macOS apps, are located in the Menu bar &amp;gt; App name &amp;gt; Preferences; in Windows, they may well be in Options, Tools, or the “Other….” The shortcuts for opening this Preferences panel widely vary as well, compared to those in macOS, which is almost always, “Command + Comma.” Most apps adapt this behavior because this is what users expect—and following expectations is, contrary to what many developers might want, the best experience for the end user. Implementing new, creative ways to organize menu items, at the cost of certain, consistent actions—essentially betraying the user—is never a good experience, who simply wants to use, not understand, the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This consistency extends not only to their other software, but also to their hardware design. The material in iOS’s user interface (the Gaussian blur “frosted glass”) is equivalent to that of macOS, tvOS, and watchOS. All fonts are of the same family—“San Francisco,” which are used not only in the UI, but are engraved in each keyboard and backplane as model numbers and specs of MacBooks and iMacs. Every charging indicator, from the MagSafe indicator light to that of the AirPods, are orange when charging, and green when charged—not only the same color, but exactly the same hue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I consider this to be a significant advantage—which can admittedly be simply dismissed as unnecessary attention to detail at the cost of other significant features—is that it greatly reduces the mental overhead, because, as mentioned, it is expected behavior. I do not want to have to learn how each of my electronic devices turn on or shut down, neither do I want to dig through each menu incomprehensibly named “Preferences,” “Options,” or “Settings,” for the things that do the same things. Windows 10, for example, has “Control Center” and “Settings,” both of which hold system configurations, which changes their share of toggles every update. I do understand Microsoft is indeed trying to unify both into the Settings app, but the end user should never have to deal with that—they should never be expected to understand, but only to simply use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next point naturally follows—Apple’s reluctancy to cling onto legacy features for the sake of backwards compatibility—rather, their despite often being criticized, is one of their major advantages. I would not go far enough to call it “courage”—as Apple often does it its keynotes—but still, it is this willingness to dispose of legacy features that allows the company to design better UX. Prematurely removing flash on iPhones&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Disregarding a physical keyboard when they introduced the first iPhone, removing the headphone jack in iPhone 7, and the home button in iPhone X, are are steps towards a more simplified, cognitively linnet user interface—as Jony Ive often denotes, their ideal iPhone would look be a touchable glass slab. I believe, with the most recent iteration, they have come remarkably close. As Youtuber Polymatter&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; offers an interning viewpoint that, to the current Apple, technology is not their core—rather, it is merely that technology happens to be the method via which they deliver their end goal. This also explains Apple’s continuous focus on Accessibility features, as their end goal is not the product, but the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A frequently missed detail on Apple’s huge profit margins, as well as their fantastic integration between products, is vertical integration. The company often emphasizes the collaboration between their hardware and software teams in their keynotes—quoting Alan Kay: “People who are really serious about software should make their own hardware.”—but this is definitely not limited to them. Not only do they design each circuit and code each line of all their products, they also control the integrated cloud service, with a single account in which one can manage everything from their app subscription to warranty services, all within a single page, all your Music with iTunes and Apple Music, your television, with Apple TV and the iTunes Store, your cloud infrastructure, with CloudKit. This is their continuous onward march towards their supposed goal of “controlling key technologies”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;—indeed, in the recent years, they came to architecture their own CPU, and more recently GPU designs, and went on to implement them in an unprecedented integration with x86 (intel) CPUs and ARM chips on their recent macs. According to some reports, they are now aiming to manufacture their display technologies—separate from Samsung, their current supplier—and are experimenting with micro-LED technologies&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of this, despite of outcries of Apple “imprisoning” their customers in their own “walled garden,” is the absolutely perfect integration, demonstrated the more products you use in their hardware ecosystem. As you approach your desk, your Mac will recognize your Apple Watch to unlock itself, and then auto-switch the music source of your AirPods to your computer, and offer in the dock to open the email you were composing on your iPhone, and restore all the browser tabs in your safari, if you ask. The recent update allows you to right-click on a text cell, and allow you to choose a menu which will prompt your iPhone camera, and auto-insert the picture in place of the cursor. Despite its limits, a walled garden is still a garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limits, however, which many Apple critics tend to offer, is very much misleading. If you are an “advanced user,” and Apple likes to say, that is familiar with the UNIX command line, you are free to customize your Mac in any way you like—Apple even offers a convenient package that lets you alter various system variables—“defaults”—and offers an open-source launch daemon—“launchd”—that users can configure fairly easily. Most apps come with AppleScript support, which which you can automate advance GUI tasks with ease, and with the 3rd-party package manager “brew,” almost all of the powerful open-source tools available in other *NIX systems can be installed with ease. The fact that many pseudo-tech enthusiasts, without a motivation to learn the almost universally accepted skill of the command line, fails to recognize its power of not only customization, but much more, reveals the fact that many of the criticisms regarding the customizability of macOS, is inherently flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A point that is made, however, is that this power is limited to macOS. Within iOS it is impossible to customize more than Apple allows you to, which is very little, without jailbreaking—which seriously undermines many of the benefits, such as the security, of iOS. Despite this, however, there is a separate case to be made with iOS as well. The limitations of iOS, although seemingly absurd, is, in my opinion, a deliberate decision. iOS is a mobile operating system, aimed to run stable for very long periods of time, without regular shutdown or downtime. This requires its developers to remove as much bugs as possible, where a force reboot may not be a viable option, more so as phones become a necessity in daily life. Limiting user customization removes the probability of unexpected configurations crashing apps, or even the system. Apple’s tight control of its apps in iOS also reveals this intention—each app in the App Store is checked for potential problems in UX or unexpected behavior, and privacy concerns, by human app reviewers, contrary to, for example, the Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus shifts now to privacy, a political and moral topic concerning the whole industry, especially in light of the Snowden leaks, or the nonconsensual data collection by Facebook. Apple has aggressively advertised its pro-user-privacy stance since the controversy with the FBI&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and despite many condemning it as a “marketing strategy,” Apple has genuine motivation—as for now—to promote the privacy of its user, mainly as most of its revenue originates from hardware, not software, and by extension, data collection.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Their advocation is not only limited to words, however, as they were one of the first to introduce two-factor authentication with Apple IDs, and their continuous efforts in preventing advertiser tracking in Safari, as far as to chip design, in which they implemented a neural engine inside the SOC of the most recent iPhone—A11 Bionic—to process computationally intensive machine learning operations not in the cloud like others, but on-device. This limits their accuracy as well as their usefulness, but a contemporary convenience at the cost of unseen future compromises of your personal data, seems to be an unfair trade-off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads nicely into the end of the rant, which, despite the ever-present feeling that I still haven’t expressed myself enough, I would like to stop here for now. I’m sure that I made myself clear enough as to why I appreciate their products. Whenever I purchase a device from Apple, I can be confident that it will be consistent and bind into the ecosystem of Apple products that I already have. I’m confident that I will not be faced with a load of minor inconveniences, and will be supported and usable a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true that you need only the right tool for the job, if you know exactly what you are going to need; but just as Apple’s directions would suggest, you don’t know them yet. It should be up to the company to figure out the minor things that make a tool useful, or the potential problems users haven’t even considered to be important—consistent user interface, tight integration, chip design and app marketplace—all of which Apple bundles up and calls “user experience.” Unless Apple takes a radical shift in these areas, or a competitor with a significantly more appealing line of products and services, I won’t be leaving my walled garden soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Steve Jobs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU&quot;&gt;Thoughts on Flash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Polymatter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zO0b-l-u7Yk&quot;&gt;Grand Theory of Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Business Insider. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/be-like-steve-own-your-key-technologies-2012-6&quot;&gt;Be Like Steve - Own Your Key Technologies.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; The Verge. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/19/17138240/apple-microled-facility-us-watch-oled&quot;&gt;Apple using secret US facility to develop MicroLED screens for Apple Watch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Wikipedia. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FBI–Apple_encryption_dispute &quot;&gt;FBI–Apple encryption dispute.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Statista. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/382260/segments-share-revenue-of-apple/&quot;&gt;Share of Apple’s revenue by product category from the first quarter of 2012 to the third quarter of 2018.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">Apple may be one of, possibly the most controversial tech company in existence, at least among those who care. So there must be a reason why I self-identify as a proud user of Apple products. I own a MacBook Pro that is 4 years old now, an iPhone 5 and iPhone 6S, and frequent our family’s iPad Pro for my drawings with the overpriced Apple Pencil. I also recently purchased my AirPods which I, despite its admittedly awkward looks, treasure. On top of that, all of my accessories, including cases, adapters, and chargers, are all Apple-branded.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Air Support</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Air Support" /><published>2018-08-07T18:04:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T18:04:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/08/07/air-support.html">&lt;p&gt;In response to a Q&amp;amp;A session with Stephen Wolfram after my summer camp, I found a particular part of one of his answers interesting. The question he was asked regarded his personal reconciliation of the discrepancies; the academic “purity” of his work—contemplating on the extents of physics, while also running a multi-national firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer was: he doesn’t. The interesting part, though, was how he described the interaction between these two categories—foundational and applied—like “air support,” as concepts devised in one are applicable on the other. This pragmatic view aligned with how I naturally seemed to perceive my own problems as well—practicing math often gives insight into social problems, algorithms for solving purely academic problems apply to real-world ones, and trivial gossip at school can leave deep insight into some interesting branches of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this imply? The principle of emergence—or as Stephen Wolfram would describe it, computational equivalence—dictates the arising complexity of applied fields. But the more fundamental subjects are abstracted far beyond what these simple connections would imply—how this “air support” apparently works. I hope to talk about this in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">In response to a Q&amp;amp;A session with Stephen Wolfram after my summer camp, I found a particular part of one of his answers interesting. The question he was asked regarded his personal reconciliation of the discrepancies; the academic “purity” of his work—contemplating on the extents of physics, while also running a multi-national firm.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Probability</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Probability" /><published>2018-08-01T21:28:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T21:28:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/08/01/probability.html">&lt;p&gt;A major shift in my perspective of how I should lead life began with considering the following prayer, by Reinhold Niebuhr (1892-1971):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;God grant me the serenity
to accept the things I cannot change; 
courage to change the things I can; 
and wisdom to know the difference.
(…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am often blinded by a false, but tempting notion that there is a way of doing that is better;  that there is always another path that will reward a better life. This idea was rooted in me by a quote from Rob Siltanen, renowned for its adoption in Apple’s “Think Different” ad campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Here’s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers. The round pegs in the square holes. The ones who see things differently. They’re not fond of rules. And they have no respect for the status quo. You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them. About the only thing you can’t do is ignore them. Because they change things. They push the human race forward. And while some may see them as the crazy ones, we see genius. Because the people who are crazy enough to think they can change the world, are the ones who do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both, at a glance equally meaningful quotes, and do seem to hold some truths. But neither can coexist, they are mutually exclusive mindsets—to accept the status quo, or to reject it. Yet either are both tempting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of my Theory of Knowledge classes, we were offered some situations and were to predict using inductive logic—e.g. the likelihood of a stock price to rise or fall, either without context, or given that it has been rising steadily the last 10 years. Smugly, I proceeded to reject all evidence and only stick to what is knowable, answering that neither is more likely in all contexts. I was surprised to find that I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a limit to understanding a perspective, and a limit to what is feasibly knowable. There is no ideal perfect information in markets, or the ability to foretell the existence of black swans before it is discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who shout life is unfair, or that it ultimately is, do not consider the intrinsic randomness that life offers to everyone. There is cause and effect and to an extent predictability, but those processes are so minuscule and microscopic that it is infeasible to try to understand. Balancing this unfairness, luck, and unpredictability, the simplest way to sum this up is to consider life as a sequence of probabilistic events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that there are too many unpredictable variables, the only choice is to stick to the things we know. We look at what we have, make estimates, and choose the path that is most likely to lead to our desired future. All we can do is to increase the number of variables we have, and learn how to interpret them more correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, if life is led by probability, not certainty or emotion, it is necessary to look after and console ourselves, and hope that our minds have the emotional strength to cope with our choices, and to take responsibility, may the result be favorable or not, the serenity, to accept the things I cannot change; courage, to change the things I can; and wisdom, to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">A major shift in my perspective of how I should lead life began with considering the following prayer, by Reinhold Niebuhr (1892-1971):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual Reality</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual Reality" /><published>2018-07-25T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/25/virtual-reality.html">&lt;p&gt;My vision with computer science start with, rather anti-climactically, with a children’s book about Chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the famous “Why?” Book-length cartoon series in Korea, the book introduced difficult chemistry concepts in a digestible children’s book. The writers, in an attempt to make the book realistic and easier to plot, set the characters in a virtual reality game, where the laws of physics, (and ironically chemistry as well) could easily be bent to facilitate explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learn more, academically, socially, or in that matter in any sense, I keep reiterating back to this imaginary world. The world, as it turns out to a depressed 8th-grader, was not a nice, cozy, neat, organized place designed for me and my friends, but a messy competition, blinded and handicapped, with the sole thread of knowledge and probability, to hang on to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was, as I observed, not out of intension, but out of inevitability. More people strive to be nice, either out of pure selflessness or a selfish desire of self-worth. Immorality, as I view it, is a result of the flaws in the system designed to handle these interactions. These systems are inevitably built upon a physical foundation, constrained by the laws of physics, and requiring heavy maintenance. Meetings need to be scheduled according to time zones, conversations cannot continue with people in different circadian rhythms, a romantic date will likely fail without a beautiful restaurant or on other sides of the world. Economies are strung by the rapid development of technology and more recently, intellectual automation, and are failing to transparently expose or fix the problems with economic crises, or the near-future result of massive unemployment, or more personally, inflation of academic or experience requirements, without it being anyone’s fault but the system’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I do see hope in many cases. The open source initiative, where programmers are voluntarily helping to develop complex programs, a community like reddit withstanding being plagued by the normal problems of social services, and the fact that these organizations and systems are capable of sustaining themselves, project a faraway, but hopeful future, where the best of humanity’s traits can shine. A technological utopia, where logistical problems are a thing of the past, and ideas and relationships can flow and prosper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems we see now, are remnants of the inevitable system of the past—just like the first books that emerged decades after the printing press was invented, we are not yet taking advantage of the accelerating technological advances of the last decade. But we do see some, advancing into and building this future, such as blockchain, machine learning, and virtual reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a virtual universe, a world can be built from scratch. A new economic system can be tested simply with a change of code, or time zones can be eliminated, or rather, will not exist in the first place. Physical distance doesn’t mean anything anymore—people can be teleported, or with a more intuitive user interface where one may just be able to think to move—or fly, or swim, or perform any other means of movement they desire. If we can parse thought, why, then, limit ourselves to our primitive bodies designed for survival? A virtualized projection of oneself can take any form, one can choose to be any animal, a robot, or anything that suits their desires—but there will be always some who choose to remain in our human forms. New forms of communication will form, and nobody will be far away from anybody. Most problems of the world, at the very least, the physical ones, will be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, of course, a far-fetched daydream. The logistics of getting us into this future, will be hindered more by economics and finance than technology. Then after by ethics, and philosophy and psychology and sociology. And then there are the practical problems in implementing the code—who designs how the world should work? Massive, multiple year-long public debates need to take place on designing and publishing the work, and when an opposition team decides to fork the brach and start a new world with different rules, the project itself will lose its purpose, as the self-aware users, us, are what ultimately gives any universe meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pleasant thought experiment for most, but this is my life-long dream. When I code, contribute to an open-source initiative, or experiment with hosting my website. Or when I learn a new concept in economics, thinking about how this system could be generalized and implemented if there were no physical hinderance. Above a certain abstraction, or more likely anything abstracted upon the natural sciences—sociology, psychology, economics, history—are subject to this consideration—how will this work without rules? If we could make this better, why? It is not only a useful mental model, but a consideration of the pure mechanics of the subject—the reason this subject exists, and is studied by humanity’s greatest minds. And it frees us from the practical consideration—if a new idea emerges, one no longer has to dismiss it as impractical or infeasible to replace, but develop it further. Ideas will no longer be judged by its physical viability, but by its intrinsic value—whatever people find that to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I name my computers and their parts with rooms, disk arrays are shelves in the basement, archival drives are the attic, and my laptop is the study—ultimately so that my full, virtual world becomes a home. My website’s subdomain is, therefore, named home. The connected world that we live in is currently a reflected version of our real world—the familiar desktop interface, the mouse, the “web,” or even the word “web-site” merely represents a physical object. When we are willing to detach from this physical world, however, those metaphors can become real, no longer reflections. We will, then finally, drop the word virtual, and live in reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">My vision with computer science start with, rather anti-climactically, with a children’s book about Chemistry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning of the End</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning of the End" /><published>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/short/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html">&lt;p&gt;Each experience in life can be lamented over as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: the gift of uniqueness and creativity, and a curse of the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then regret becomes, on some level, a balance between the boundaries of these two sides: the more things you consider part of a general whole, the less regret you have, but the less preciseness you feel. “The sun will rise tomorrow” instills hope and therefore implies a lack of regret, but as a consequence each day is stripped of its significance. On the other hand if one was to obsess on the unique weather of each day, then they would be astonished and amazed every day simply staring up at the sky, but would be full of disappointment at that this will end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common Japanese phrase “when you start hoping for this moment thing to last, it is the beginning of the end.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">Each experience in life can be lamented over as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: the gift of uniqueness and creativity, and a curse of the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should like studying</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should like studying" /><published>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html">&lt;p&gt;Not many of my fellow classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me, enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but work itself—is an abnormality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A necessary detail is that my school is not subject to most problems plaguing many high schools—our teachers are passionate, insightful, and never decline a request for help. There are no serious social issues, and especially since the school is so small, everyone is part of a tightly-knit group. So some of my observation and experiences might be limited to my own school, and I do not deny that many of these insights are only obtainable in a well-maintained education system. But I still do argue that this is how one should approach learning, regardless of their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should not consider studying as work per se. In my “Why Be Productive” essay, I discussed the subtle distinctions between contribution and maintenance. Studying, at a high school level, is preparation for such contribution. You are given, through education, the building blocks with which you can create and contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be why many might indeed feel that what they are learning is “useless.” Maintenance does not require abstract or critical thinking skills—a part-time cashier will benefit nothing from their calculus class, as well as most white-collar workers. The real meaning of studying these subjects are in that they provide the ingredients for thinking—an insight into a particular school of thought. Such flexible thinking is required in almost all but the most physical labor—which are now mostly automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a more idealistic point of view, these ingredients will work to contribute, and the goal of higher level education would be to push the human race forward, in the hopes that everyone capable would be creating and advancing civilization each moment. Like the term “Liberal Arts” that imply the necessity of education, in that one is imprisoned by the lack of knowledge, education, ideally, is the necessary process that puts everyone at the level in which they have the choice to create, whether they take the path or not. It would be immoral not to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, though, studying is unavoidable to fair well in life. Especially in my culture, good grades do decide a major portion of life—even as much as luck. I cannot deny such a fear is also a subconscious motivation for me “liking” studying—but I do try to enjoy it as much as possible. A major personal paradigm shift in my viewpoint was when I took advanced physics courses during the end of 8th grade. Learning up to a point where you are told that this is the forefront of this subject—and especially when that subject is one that aims to describe how this universe operates, shows, first, that there are no insurmountable mountains of knowledge, that there is an end to every subject; and second, a picture of myself advancing into the further uncharted territories. Confidence, and curiosity, is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this paradigm, each subject reveals its own appeal. Physics gives you the foundations for your world view (one potential, fundamental truth), and states that all you and everything else in the universe are, are twelve particles interacting in specific ways. Chemistry describes how these particles come together to form an atom, and again how they come together to interact in interesting ways. Biology, leading somewhat to our own bias towards ourselves, specializes in how these interactions make up living things, while Neuroscience further specializes in the brain. Psychology describes how a brain might behave, and Sociology describes how a bunch of brains can come together to form patterns and regulations in behavior. Economics, or Political science has an additional layer of artificial separation—capitalism, and democracy, communism, etc.—whose ideas we actually live in.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most students, I believe, may stand on the top of this mountainous stack, but have no knowledge of what they stand upon. I still do not understand each piece of this mountain that I am standing on, and nobody will ever. However, what I do know is the system with which this monument of human knowledge is built upon, the protocols in which new blocks are added, and a vague grasp of each major structural part. This is what makes studying interesting for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Math and Computer Science, though, is different. I hope to address that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">Not many of my fellow classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me, enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but work itself—is an abnormality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Be Productive?</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Be Productive?" /><published>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html">&lt;p&gt;The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, work is nobody’s favorite subject. Yet, contrary to this obvious intuition, I find such techniques and systems deeply interesting, diving deeper than what would be practical. The kickstart of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained somewhat of an admiration of this discipline of self-discipline, as I often do with topics of such sort. I hope to introduce my personal reason for such a choice, and outline a few actual techniques that I actually implement, in hopes of that it might aid anybody in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for wasting time on unnecessarily deep investigations on raising efficiency (like this essay) is, somewhat ironically, to maximize freedom. Work should not interfere with my day when I occasionally want to stay in bed until noon, or take a long walk in the evening on a weekday. Disciplining yourself, therefore, would be equivalent to buying time for your future self; a way of allowing my future self to focus on what I want, rather than what I have to do. I sometimes fantasize a device that allows for saving and restoring time; one might decide to save an hour of commuting time (during which they would be unconscious), and later use it when necessary (stopping the world around them). Choosing to be productive is the closest we can approach this fantasy, as the problem of time management is always procrastination, and the that of deadlines is not lack of time, but of discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we were to suppose a future in which we could control time, it would not be far-fetched to assume that similar technology would have freed us from mandatory labor. In an ideal world, nobody would be required to work—despite the talk of the “contributions to society,” or “giving back what you got,” meaningful contributions to humanity are driven not by money, but rather passion or interest—those who find meaning in creating, would continue to create regardless of whether they get something in return or not. Most jobs currently in existence will be automated in the near future (e.g. via machine learning or similar inventions) and therefore are far from contributions, and closer to maintenance. Critical roles in our economic or political system (i.e. government officials or bankers), are simply jobs that lubricate the gears that turn the wheels of society, and despite the importance and indispensability of such work in contemporary society, they do not offer advancements to humanity. Most contemporary work is subject to simple or complex physical mechanization, and as intellectual automation begins to permeate the world, most jobs—including those that form the crux of our intricate frameworks—would become meaningless. Freedom from labor, intellectual or physical, is, therefore, the ultimate goal of increasing productivity. The end goal isn’t to balance work, but rather to remove it.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then what is meaningful work? This closely relates to my interpretation of freedom—when one is free to do whatever they want, then some, may that be a very small proportion, would choose to create. Creativity in not only the arts, but in all academic disciplines, increasing the database of human knowledge, and endlessly approaching a truth, however one might interpret the concept. In any case, anybody would be able to pursue anything they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can ignore the philosophical implications of such an ideal world, though, as we return to more practical implementations of productivity (more so because I would not be versed enough in the subject to spark such discussions). The key to efficiency is minimalism—reducing the overhead in every task. This includes automating repetitive and dull tasks if possible (easier in computational tasks than physical ones)—such as stockpiling supplies or scripting workflows. Simplicity is crucial in maintaining efficiency, as (in my experience) our minds are not well-equipped for complexity greater than a certain threshold. This is not to be confused with visual complexity—a clean room can be efficient, but a dirty room in which its owner can easily locate everything is equally economical. Similar to one of the design goals of Apple’s redesign of iOS in 2013—“Bringing order to complexity”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;—the mental overhead, not the physical, is what needs reduction. If something, whether it be an idea, project, or an object, is unnecessary, throw it out. If it isn’t, organize it in within a system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system of organization is something one can be a bit more flexible about, as discovering what works for you appears to be more important than following a central dogma. I personally use the tools developed around a system called Getting Things Done&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, outlined in a book with the same name, but don’t follow its methodologies. The program is called Omnifocus, in which I collect any ideas or due tasks, which are then formatted and organized into subsections called Projects. Other features are minor conveniences, but the crucial part of any program, or even a paper-based system is the ability to capture every drifting idea, and then to organize and display them when needed. For example, if I were to think of a topic for a blog post, the task manager would be responsible for recording what I tell it about my thought, organizing it into the right projects (giving enough information), and displaying it when I sit down to write. This process is rather a popular one, and is outlined in a short and informative video from CrashCourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One must, however, be aware of the time cost for managing this system, relative to the cost of actually executing each task. This problem is a common and well documented occurrence&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Another trap that can be more subtle, but equally dangerous, is that of endless self-improvement. That is, internalizing barriers in tasks, rather than identifying and addressing an external issue. An article about a more generalized version of this problem can be found in the link&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lengthy words of caution in this post, and the endless possibility of improvement, increasing productivity can be a rewarding and interesting experience, given that one avoids the common pitfalls and misconceptions. I am still in the midst of altering my system or organization, and I do not see my journey ending quite soon yet, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is an additional list of minor but helpful mental models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a task costs less than a threshold (e.g. 5 minutes), do it immediately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A self-aware disciplinary task accomplished first in the morning effectively increases motivation for the rest of the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; CGPGrey. Humans Need Not Apply. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; “Jony Ive Debuts iOS 7: ‘Bringing Order To Complexity’”. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; techcrunch.com/2013/06/11/jony-ives-debutes-ios-7-bringing-order-to-complexity/. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Crash Course Efficiency &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; XKCD. Efficiency. https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/efficiency.png. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Improving Ourselves to Death. https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/01/15/improving-ourselves-to-death. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, work is nobody’s favorite subject. Yet, contrary to this obvious intuition, I find such techniques and systems deeply interesting, diving deeper than what would be practical. The kickstart of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained somewhat of an admiration of this discipline of self-discipline, as I often do with topics of such sort. I hope to introduce my personal reason for such a choice, and outline a few actual techniques that I actually implement, in hopes of that it might aid anybody in need.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Math and Computer Science</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Math and Computer Science" /><published>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was part of an essay for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of mathematics, I believe, is what describes the very nature of who we are — inevitably, though, as the world itself, in my understanding, may be just a complex application of math. Zooming out, however, cryptography and number theory, but more so mathematics in general, are both subjects of my greatest passion, in their practical application, but more in their elegance and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was an elementary school student in Korea, I was recommended a book called “The Mathematics Shop,” which told the stories of Pythagoras’s theorem, Euclidian geometry, or Gauss’s Seven Bridges of Königsberg with pictures and stories. For me, the book contained, more than anything, stories that told me how our world works—math was a story that played in the theatre called the universe. It engraved, in my immature mind, a principle that I would later discover to be the base of my personality: that our universe is fundamentally a mathematical one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very personal but quite common first encounter with number theory, for me, was with the Goldbach’s conjecture. Another mathematics book recommended to me by my middle school Korean math teacher told a fictional story about a mathematician attempting, although failing, to prove the conjecture. For a Korean 7th-grade student, math was something to despise and hate, as a subject that brings down your grades. This book broke this overshadowing perception that mathematics is a problem-solving subject—that practicing mathematics is much different than learning it, and more importantly, that it is a human subject, that requires creativity as much as insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I researched for more information on these fields, but soon realized that without formal education my understanding was limited. I asked my teachers for recommendations, who pointed me to summer courses at nearby schools, in which I took courses in basic discrete mathematics, number theory, and combinatorics. The foundations of these subjects help me through my current courses, but more importantly, helped me realize early on what I was “missing out on.” There were whole worlds of mathematics that were explored, and that I have never seen before. This was when I saw how deep this field can go, and how naive I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, with a connection with my interest in computer science, I discovered how interesting the field of cryptography can be, on a mathematical level. My math research project assessment in my first year of IB, was a chance to show my interests in these fields, and I chose my topic in cryptography: a mathematical analysis of the encryption device Enigma machine. In the abstract of the research paper in which I discussed the encryption mechanisms of the device as well as how it was broken, I expressed the reason for my choice of topic, that I would like to &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption.html&quot;&gt;share&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now pursuing mathematics in my IB Mathematics Higher Level course, while also preparing for AP Calculus exam in May. The knowledge I gain from these courses, however, as I see now, are merely tools in practicing mathematics. I am now only halfway—or even less—done climbing to the figurative shoulders of giants; what I might me able to witness at the top of them, how much more of the world I can make sense, is what excites me to try every new opportunity to learn math.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This was part of an essay for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp" /><published>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This report can also be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stmaur.ac.jp/news/science/three-days-ysfh-science-immersion-camp&quot;&gt;school website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my interest in science, I have always fulfilled my scientific curiosity in solitude; most of my friends did not have as deep a level of appreciation towards the subject as I did, and my teachers had priorities of teaching everyone together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say, however, that I did not consider science as a fundamentally collaborative  activity. I am aware most research or studies are done as a team, and even if a person works alone, they would not get too far without advice, or any previous work. As Newton once said, “I am standing on the shoulders of giants;” it is just that I haven’t done really exciting, collaborative, science before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the experience during the Science Immersion Camp was quite new to me. First, there was the fact that this was school mainly taught in Japanese; I was unfamiliar with the Japanese school culture, and I initially had a hard time communicating with my buddy. One particular thing, however, that we both were interest in, was physics; he was planning to take the subject next year, and I was thrilled to find somebody that was genuinely interested in it—not as an academic subject, but as a true interest. I was able to break the ice with some physics discussion, and also got comfortable with my group members during the process. I was surprised to meet a person in my age group that all shared the same excitement towards science, and that talking about it was considered a natural conversational topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, was the classes. Though I am lucky to study in a school equipped with various scientific equipments, I have to admit, the facilities in the Science Frontier High school was more advanced. The majority of the classes I took was in the labs, and with practical experiments—many that I only learned in theory. It was fascinating to see results that matched the theories that I had learned. I especially enjoyed the astronomy class, during which we calculated the age of the universe using Hubble’s constant, calculated by spectral data collected from real observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the closing assembly, one of the guest teachers said that the basis for scientific research is communication, and more and more of that is done in English. I was lucky to participate in this camp which not only taught me, but let me experience those words myself, and shifted my view on how science is done—with communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This report can also be found on my school website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughs on Encryption</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughs on Encryption" /><published>2017-09-05T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/excerpt/2017/09/05/thoughts-on-encryption.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an extract from the rational of my research on the Enigma Machine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encryption is a crucial part in our lives in this age of information. For all practical purposes, however, encryption may seem to be unneeded; Assuming everybody is well-purposed and are “nice” people, there is no reason to hide information. However, by nature humans desire privacy, and that desire is one of the fundamental principles of our complicated modern society. Whether it is to keep military secrets, or to hide your embarrassing texts with your ex-boyfriend, encryption, I believe, represents a technology solely developed for humans. Our craving for privacy and secrecy is what defines our unique identity, and encryption is what enables us to do so in the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another significant fact about the Engima machine is that it was defeated. The fact that the first encryption device, thought to be unbreakable, was broken, reveals how every encryption method is capable of being exploited, and the designer should always keep that fact in mind. Modern encryption methods, however complicated, is theoretically breakable; the currently widely-used RSA algorithms can be defeated using a quantum algorithm; and there have already been advances in replacement technologies for when quantum computing would become mainstream. This shows the basic incompleteness of encryption, and that there is no “perfect” method, only a better one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By understanding the mathematics behind the Enigma and the Bombe, I believe I would gain a better understanding of the fundamental ideas behind encryption; how, but more importantly, why, we design encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/Enigma/index.html&quot;&gt;full research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pyokyeong Son</name></author><summary type="html">This is an extract from the rational of my research on the Enigma Machine.</summary></entry></feed>