<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-22T21:17:54+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/</id><title type="html">PK’s Blog</title><subtitle>This is Pyokyeong's Blog.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">short - Beginning of the End</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="short - Beginning of the End" /><published>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T21:17:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/22/short-beginning-of-the-end.html">&lt;p&gt;Each experience in life can be lamented over as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: the gift of uniqueness and creativity, and a curse of the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then regret becomes, on some level, a balance between the boundaries of these two sides: the more things you consider part of a general whole, the less regret you have, but the less preciseness you feel. “The sun will rise tomorrow” instills hope and therefore implies a lack of regret, but as a consequence each day is stripped of its significance. On the other hand if one was to obsess on the unique weather of each day, then they would be astonished and amazed every day simply staring up at the sky, but would be full of disappointment at that this will end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common Japanese phrase “when you start hoping for this moment thing to last, it is the beginning of the end.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Each experience in life can be lamented over as a the single, unique, “one-time” experience—each moment, therefore is simultaneously a gift and a curse: the gift of uniqueness and creativity, and a curse of the irreversibility, the irrevocability of the event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should like studying</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should like studying" /><published>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/why-I-like-studying.html">&lt;p&gt;Not many of my fellow classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me, enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but work itself—is an abnormality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A necessary detail is that my school is not subject to most problems plaguing many high schools—our teachers are passionate, insightful, and never decline a request for help. There are no serious social issues, and especially since the school is so small, everyone is part of a tightly-knit group. So some of my observation and experiences might be limited to my own school, and I do not deny that many of these insights are only obtainable in a well-maintained education system. But I still do argue that this is how one should approach learning, regardless of their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should not consider studying as work per se. In my “Why Be Productive” essay, I discussed the subtle distinctions between contribution and maintenance. Studying, at a high school level, is preparation for such contribution. You are given, through education, the building blocks with which you can create and contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be why many might indeed feel that what they are learning is “useless.” Maintenance does not require abstract or critical thinking skills—a part-time cashier will benefit nothing from their calculus class, as well as most white-collar workers. The real meaning of studying these subjects are in that they provide the ingredients for thinking—an insight into a particular school of thought. Such flexible thinking is required in almost all but the most physical labor—which are now mostly automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a more idealistic point of view, these ingredients will work to contribute, and the goal of higher level education would be to push the human race forward, in the hopes that everyone capable would be creating and advancing civilization each moment. Like the term “Liberal Arts” that imply the necessity of education, in that one is imprisoned by the lack of knowledge, education, ideally, is the necessary process that puts everyone at the level in which they have the choice to create, whether they take the path or not. It would be immoral not to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, though, studying is unavoidable to fair well in life. Especially in my culture, good grades do decide a major portion of life—even as much as luck. I cannot deny such a fear is also a subconscious motivation for me “liking” studying—but I do try to enjoy it as much as possible. A major personal paradigm shift in my viewpoint was when I took advanced physics courses during the end of 8th grade. Learning up to a point where you are told that this is the forefront of this subject—and especially when that subject is one that aims to describe how this universe operates, shows, first, that there are no insurmountable mountains of knowledge, that there is an end to every subject; and second, a picture of myself advancing into the further uncharted territories. Confidence, and curiosity, is what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this paradigm, each subject reveals its own appeal. Physics gives you the foundations for your world view (one potential, fundamental truth), and states that all you and everything else in the universe are, are twelve particles interacting in specific ways. Chemistry describes how these particles come together to form an atom, and again how they come together to interact in interesting ways. Biology, leading somewhat to our own bias towards ourselves, specializes in how these interactions make up living things, while Neuroscience further specializes in the brain. Psychology describes how a brain might behave, and Sociology describes how a bunch of brains can come together to form patterns and regulations in behavior. Economics, or Political science has an additional layer of artificial separation—capitalism, and democracy, communism, etc.—whose ideas we actually live in.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most students, I believe, may stand on the top of this mountainous stack, but have no knowledge of what they stand upon. I still do not understand each piece of this mountain that I am standing on, and nobody will ever. However, what I do know is the system with which this monument of human knowledge is built upon, the protocols in which new blocks are added, and a vague grasp of each major structural part. This is what makes studying interesting for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Math and Computer Science, though, is different. I hope to address that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Not many of my fellow classmates understand when I say that one of my favorite hobbies is studying—they know why it’s important, but not how to enjoy it. They often seem to have better things to do, than to sit around and work all day. In their eyes, me, enjoying schoolwork—not just a single subject, but work itself—is an abnormality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Computers and Myself</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/computers-and-myself.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computers and Myself" /><published>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T08:58:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/computers-and-myself</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/21/computers-and-myself.html">&lt;p&gt;I often imagine myself as a computer. Specifically, a supercomputer in a datacenter—crunching away abstract, but delicately meaningful numbers, without exceptions or mistakes. I have a redundant, and fully error-correcting filesystem—a memory palace—to store important information. I have a logging system—a diary—to store the errors and exceptions from my programs. New tasks are fed through a structured queue—my planner—to be processed when idle. Sometimes, but not too often, there is a power outage, so somebody else would have to come in to power cycle me a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a mental model that I’ve had for many years, so naturally, I cannot help but feel companionship with my fellow computers—my laptop, and home server, both of which have been given names too endearing to publicize. When I talk to it, sometimes through a mouse and a pointer, sometimes through a keyboard and a terminal, I see a reflection of myself, an entity, housing a world of its own. Not as in that it feels like a person, but in that, even after fully studying its mechanical, logical components, I see a personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind its outer skin—the screen, the keyboard, and the mouse—are layers and layers of precisely organized abstractions, under which lie electronic switches that simply block or pass through a current—that is all that a computer is, and will ever be—a collection of code. Arranging these transistors to perform basic logic operations, to perform arithmetic, then to store binary information, then to cycle through these operations at regular intervals: the piles and piles of ingenious designs, delicately arranged upon the silicon, brings personality to these lifeless components. I dare draw an analogy with the emergence of life; a set of inanimate chemicals undergoing rule-bound reactions, executed exactly inside a thin layer of lipids, that come together to perform certain functions, precisely according to its code, its DNA. This is what life, in principle, is. Is a computer any different? A computer is simply a being made from different materials, with a little less complex, and that had a little less time to evolve, than the soft biological machines that we are. The intelligence that it may house, nevertheless, is no different from ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence is, to me, a proof-of-concept field that undermines what we normally think of as intelligence. With a simple idea—a perceptron—and few hundred lines of code, a computer can learn to read numbers. With another idea—convolution—and a few more hundred, it can see a picture. With sufficient complexity, a computer may, very possibly, achieve intelligence on the level of, or even surpassing that of, humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember in a computer science class—in 2nd grade—when I, sitting in front of a desktop screen, wondered: Who is doing all of this? Is there a person on the other end controlling all of this? Is there somebody, some living, thinking being that is putting this on the screen? Despite the sheer ignorance of this 10-year-old child, in hindsight, his question may be at the core of my fixation on this field. I imagine a time where computers have achieved enough complexity and intelligence that the question may redeem true, and that in fact there is a thinking being on the other side. That being might be thoughtful enough to imagine itself as a person—and I may be lucky enough to contribute a verse to its code.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I often imagine myself as a computer. Specifically, a supercomputer in a datacenter—crunching away abstract, but delicately meaningful numbers, without exceptions or mistakes. I have a redundant, and fully error-correcting filesystem—a memory palace—to store important information. I have a logging system—a diary—to store the errors and exceptions from my programs. New tasks are fed through a structured queue—my planner—to be processed when idle. Sometimes, but not too often, there is a power outage, so somebody else would have to come in to power cycle me a few times.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Be Productive?</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Be Productive?" /><published>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T21:38:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/07/20/why-be-productive.html">&lt;p&gt;The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, work is nobody’s favorite subject. Yet, contrary to this obvious intuition, I find such techniques and systems deeply interesting, diving deeper than what would be practical. The kickstart of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained somewhat of an admiration of this discipline of self-discipline, as I often do with topics of such sort. I hope to introduce my personal reason for such a choice, and outline a few actual techniques that I actually implement, in hopes of that it might aid anybody in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for wasting time on unnecessarily deep investigations on raising efficiency (like this essay) is, somewhat ironically, to maximize freedom. Work should not interfere with my day when I occasionally want to stay in bed until noon, or take a long walk in the evening on a weekday. Disciplining yourself, therefore, would be equivalent to buying time for your future self; a way of allowing my future self to focus on what I want, rather than what I have to do. I sometimes fantasize a device that allows for saving and restoring time; one might decide to save an hour of commuting time (during which they would be unconscious), and later use it when necessary (stopping the world around them). Choosing to be productive is the closest we can approach this fantasy, as the problem of time management is always procrastination, and the that of deadlines is not lack of time, but of discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we were to suppose a future in which we could control time, it would not be far-fetched to assume that similar technology would have freed us from mandatory labor. In an ideal world, nobody would be required to work—despite the talk of the “contributions to society,” or “giving back what you got,” meaningful contributions to humanity are driven not by money, but rather passion or interest—those who find meaning in creating, would continue to create regardless of whether they get something in return or not. Most jobs currently in existence will be automated in the near future (e.g. via machine learning or similar inventions) and therefore are far from contributions, and closer to maintenance. Critical roles in our economic or political system (i.e. government officials or bankers), are simply jobs that lubricate the gears that turn the wheels of society, and despite the importance and indispensability of such work in contemporary society, they do not offer advancements to humanity. Most contemporary work is subject to simple or complex physical mechanization, and as intellectual automation begins to permeate the world, most jobs—including those that form the crux of our intricate frameworks—would become meaningless. Freedom from labor, intellectual or physical, is, therefore, the ultimate goal of increasing productivity. The end goal isn’t to balance work, but rather to remove it.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then what is meaningful work? This closely relates to my interpretation of freedom—when one is free to do whatever they want, then some, may that be a very small proportion, would choose to create. Creativity in not only the arts, but in all academic disciplines, increasing the database of human knowledge, and endlessly approaching a truth, however one might interpret the concept. In any case, anybody would be able to pursue anything they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can ignore the philosophical implications of such an ideal world, though, as we return to more practical implementations of productivity (more so because I would not be versed enough in the subject to spark such discussions). The key to efficiency is minimalism—reducing the overhead in every task. This includes automating repetitive and dull tasks if possible (easier in computational tasks than physical ones)—such as stockpiling supplies or scripting workflows. Simplicity is crucial in maintaining efficiency, as (in my experience) our minds are not well-equipped for complexity greater than a certain threshold. This is not to be confused with visual complexity—a clean room can be efficient, but a dirty room in which its owner can easily locate everything is equally economical. Similar to one of the design goals of Apple’s redesign of iOS in 2013—“Bringing order to complexity”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;—the mental overhead, not the physical, is what needs reduction. If something, whether it be an idea, project, or an object, is unnecessary, throw it out. If it isn’t, organize it in within a system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system of organization is something one can be a bit more flexible about, as discovering what works for you appears to be more important than following a central dogma. I personally use the tools developed around a system called Getting Things Done&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, outlined in a book with the same name, but don’t follow its methodologies. The program is called Omnifocus, in which I collect any ideas or due tasks, which are then formatted and organized into subsections called Projects. Other features are minor conveniences, but the crucial part of any program, or even a paper-based system is the ability to capture every drifting idea, and then to organize and display them when needed. For example, if I were to think of a topic for a blog post, the task manager would be responsible for recording what I tell it about my thought, organizing it into the right projects (giving enough information), and displaying it when I sit down to write. This process is rather a popular one, and is outlined in a short and informative video from CrashCourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One must, however, be aware of the time cost for managing this system, relative to the cost of actually executing each task. This problem is a common and well documented occurrence&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Another trap that can be more subtle, but equally dangerous, is that of endless self-improvement. That is, internalizing barriers in tasks, rather than identifying and addressing an external issue. An article about a more generalized version of this problem can be found in the link&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lengthy words of caution in this post, and the endless possibility of improvement, increasing productivity can be a rewarding and interesting experience, given that one avoids the common pitfalls and misconceptions. I am still in the midst of altering my system or organization, and I do not see my journey ending quite soon yet, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is an additional list of minor but helpful mental models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a task costs less than a threshold (e.g. 5 minutes), do it immediately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A self-aware disciplinary task accomplished first in the morning effectively increases motivation for the rest of the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; CGPGrey. Humans Need Not Apply. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; “Jony Ive Debuts iOS 7: ‘Bringing Order To Complexity’”. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; techcrunch.com/2013/06/11/jony-ives-debutes-ios-7-bringing-order-to-complexity/. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Crash Course Efficiency &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; XKCD. Efficiency. https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/efficiency.png. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Improving Ourselves to Death. https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/01/15/improving-ourselves-to-death. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The journey to productivity is more often motivated by need than interest, as, one would arguably assume, work is nobody’s favorite subject. Yet, contrary to this obvious intuition, I find such techniques and systems deeply interesting, diving deeper than what would be practical. The kickstart of this journey was, even for me, out of necessity—but gradually I gained somewhat of an admiration of this discipline of self-discipline, as I often do with topics of such sort. I hope to introduce my personal reason for such a choice, and outline a few actual techniques that I actually implement, in hopes of that it might aid anybody in need.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Math and CS</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Math and CS" /><published>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2018/06/10/math-and-computer-science.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was part of an application form for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of mathematics, I believe, is what describes the very nature of who we are — inevitably, though, as the world itself, in my understanding, may be just a complex application of math. Zooming out, however, cryptography and number theory, but more so mathematics in general, are both subjects of my greatest passion, in their practical application, but more in their elegance and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was an elementary school student in Korea, I was recommended a book called “The Mathematics Shop,” which told the stories of Pythagoras’s theorem, Euclidian geometry, or Gauss’s Seven Bridges of Königsberg with pictures and stories. For me, the book contained, more than anything, stories that told me how our world works—math was a story that played in the theatre called the universe. It engraved, in my immature mind, a principle that I would later discover to be the base of my personality: that our universe is fundamentally a mathematical one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very personal but quite common first encounter with number theory, for me, was with the Goldbach’s conjecture. Another mathematics book recommended to me by my middle school Korean math teacher told a fictional story about a mathematician attempting, although failing, to prove the conjecture. For a Korean 7th-grade student, math was something to despise and hate, as a subject that brings down your grades. This book broke this overshadowing perception that mathematics is a problem-solving subject—that practicing mathematics is much different than learning it, and more importantly, that it is a human subject, that requires creativity as much as insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I researched for more information on these fields, but soon realized that without formal education my understanding was limited. I asked my teachers for recommendations, who pointed me to summer courses at nearby schools, in which I took courses in basic discrete mathematics, number theory, and combinatorics. The foundations of these subjects help me through my current courses, but more importantly, helped me realize early on what I was “missing out on.” There were whole worlds of mathematics that were explored, and that I have never seen before. This was when I saw how deep this field can go, and how naive I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, with a connection with my interest in computer science, I discovered how interesting the field of cryptography can be, on a mathematical level. My math research project assessment in my first year of IB, was a chance to show my interests in these fields, and I chose my topic in cryptography: a mathematical analysis of the encryption device Enigma machine. In the abstract of the research paper in which I discussed the encryption mechanisms of the device as well as how it was broken, I expressed the reason for my choice of topic, that I would like to &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption.html&quot;&gt;share&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now pursuing mathematics in my IB Mathematics Higher Level course, while also preparing for AP Calculus exam in May. The knowledge I gain from these courses, however, as I see now, are merely tools in practicing mathematics. I am now only halfway—or even less—done climbing to the figurative shoulders of giants; what I might me able to witness at the top of them, how much more of the world I can make sense, is what excites me to try every new opportunity to learn math.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This was part of an application form for a summer college course in Number Theory and Cryptography.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Thoughs on Encryption</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Thoughs on Encryption" /><published>2017-12-01T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/12/01/thoughts-on-encryption.html">&lt;p&gt;This is an extract from the rational of my research on the Enigma Machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encryption is a crucial part in our lives in this age of information. For all practical purposes, however, encryption may seem to be unneeded; Assuming everybody is well-purposed and are “nice” people, there is no reason to hide information. However, by nature humans desire privacy, and that desire is one of the fundamental principles of our complicated modern society. Whether it is to keep military secrets, or to hide your embarrassing texts with your ex-boyfriend, encryption , I believe, represents a technology solely developed for humans. Our craving for privacy and secrecy is what defines our unique identity, and encryption is what enables us to do so in the digital world.
Another significant fact about the Engima machine is that it was defeated. The fact that the first encryption device, thought to be unbreakable, was broken, reveals how every encryption method is capable of being exploited, and the designer should always keep that fact in mind. Modern encryption methods, however complicated, is theoretically breakable; the currently widely-used RSA algorithms can be defeated using a quantum algorithm; and there have already been advances in replacement technologies for when quantum computing would become mainstream. This shows the basic incompleteness of encryption, and that there is no “perfect” method, only a better one.
By understanding the mathematics behind the Enigma and the Bombe, I believe I would gain a better understanding of the fundamental ideas behind encryption; how, but more importantly, why, we design encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/Enigma/index.html&quot;&gt;full research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is an extract from the rational of my research on the Enigma Machine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp</title><link href="https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Days at the YSFH Science Immersion Camp" /><published>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-11-02T21:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pyoky.me/blog/2017/11/02/science-immersion-camp.html">&lt;p&gt;This report can also be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stmaur.ac.jp/news/science/three-days-ysfh-science-immersion-camp&quot;&gt;school website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my interest in science, I have always fulfilled my scientific curiosity in solitude; most of my friends did not have as deep a level of appreciation towards the subject as I did, and my teachers had priorities of teaching everyone together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say, however, that I did not consider science as a fundamentally collaborative  activity. I am aware most research or studies are done as a team, and even if a person works alone, they would not get too far without advice, or any previous work. As Newton once said, “I am standing on the shoulders of giants;” it is just that I haven’t done really exciting, collaborative, science before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the experience during the Science Immersion Camp was quite new to me. First, there was the fact that this was school mainly taught in Japanese; I was unfamiliar with the Japanese school culture, and I initially had a hard time communicating with my buddy. One particular thing, however, that we both were interest in, was physics; he was planning to take the subject next year, and I was thrilled to find somebody that was genuinely interested in it—not as an academic subject, but as a true interest. I was able to break the ice with some physics discussion, and also got comfortable with my group members during the process. I was surprised to meet a person in my age group that all shared the same excitement towards science, and that talking about it was considered a natural conversational topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, was the classes. Though I am lucky to study in a school equipped with various scientific equipments, I have to admit, the facilities in the Science Frontier High school was more advanced. The majority of the classes I took was in the labs, and with practical experiments—many that I only learned in theory. It was fascinating to see results that matched the theories that I had learned. I especially enjoyed the astronomy class, during which we calculated the age of the universe using Hubble’s constant, calculated by spectral data collected from real observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the closing assembly, one of the guest teachers said that the basis for scientific research is communication, and more and more of that is done in English. I was lucky to participate in this camp which not only taught me, but let me experience those words myself, and shifted my view on how science is done—with communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This report can also be found on my school website.</summary></entry></feed>