<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>PK&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://pyoky.me/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on PK&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>main diagonal</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/main-diagonal</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/main-diagonal</guid>
    <description>Main Diagonal Anti-diagonal .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Agents of the Macro Economy</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Agents-of-the-Macro-Economy</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Agents-of-the-Macro-Economy</guid>
    <description>Agents § We’re doing static analysis; i.e. it’s very LR or very SR. Numerous agents of each sector are grouped into a representative agent. Representative household Objective: maximize utility over consumption (C) and Leisure (L) within the utility function → Labor Supply SN and # of laborers N → Goods Demanded D Representative Firm Objective: maximuze profit (π) over capital (K) and Labor (N) within the production function → Labor Demand DN → Goods Supplied S Government Role: collect taxes and pay transfers (NT); spend remaining on the goods market G Household Optimization § For households the price of consumption goods and the price of leisure [=wage] is an exogenous variable; i.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Algorithm Problem Tips</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm-Problem-Tips</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm-Problem-Tips</guid>
    <description>During Practice § There are only two ways to store data structures: as arrays (sequential storage) or as linked lists (linked storage). First of all, it should be clear that data structures are tools, and algorithms are methods to solve specific problems with appropriate tools.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Algorithm</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm</guid>
    <description>Loose definition Note An algorithm… finishes in finite number of steps its answer is consistent it always gives the correct answer Algorithm Design Principles § Design What to compute How it computes what we want it to compute Correctness Why does it compute what we want it to compute Analysis &amp; Efficiency How much resources does it use? (Complexity) Most algorithms follow the following two standard models of computation Recursion Iteration Verifying Correctness § Warning There is no way to find out if an algorithm is correct.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Alienation</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Alienation</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Alienation</guid>
    <description>Commoditization of human labor § Trading labor Differences of age and sex have no longer any distinctive social validity for the working class. All are instruments of labour, more or less expensive to use, according to their age and sex.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Amartya Sen</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Amartya-Sen</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Amartya-Sen</guid>
    <description> Developer of the Human Development Index Author of (Article) Equality of What? Frequent interactions with Martha Nussbaum .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Analytic Philosophy</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Analytic-Philosophy</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Analytic-Philosophy</guid>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Anarcho-Syndicalism</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Anarcho-Syndicalism</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Anarcho-Syndicalism</guid>
    <description>Noam Chomsky Anarcho-: Decentralization of power Syndicalism: Worker’s union’s ownership of Means of Production A realistic alternative to Marxism .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Annuity</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Annuity</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Annuity</guid>
    <description>Annuities are… Money you borrowed: mortgages, etc. ⇒ pay regularly to pay off large amount Money you lent: social security credit, etc. ⇒ give large money, get regular payments later Amortization is the same thing but from a different perspective ⇒ You’re spreading a one-time cost into multiple years.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Approximating Distributions</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximating-Distributions</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximating-Distributions</guid>
    <description>thm. A Normal Distribution with μ=np,σ=np(1−p)​ will approximate a Binomial distribution with n trials and success probability p when np&gt;1 P(a≤X≤b)=k=a∑b​P(X=k)≃∫ab​fnormal​(μ=np,σ=np(1−p)​)dx REMARK.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 20:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>