<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>PK&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://pyoky.me/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on PK&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Dynamic Programming</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Dynamic-Programming</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Dynamic-Programming</guid>
    <description> The name &quot;Dynamic Programming&quot; is a misnomer. Motto of Dynamic Programming Dynamic Programming (DP) is a algorithm design paradigm that includes the following features: Algorithms are recursive There are overlapping recursive subproblems Memoization can be used to reduce re-solving overlapping subproblems You can also write an iterative solution which can be easier to analyze Think of DP as a &quot;filling in a table&quot; problem To devise a DP solution to a problem, you must Understand which subproblems overlap Recursion trees help in identifying overlap Understand the subproblem dependencies (which subproblems to solve first) How to break ties (e.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>EBITDA Multiple</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/EBITDA-Multiple</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/EBITDA-Multiple</guid>
    <description>def. Enterprise value. The amout of money you have to pay to buy off the company, including its financial oblications (net debt) Enterprise Value = Equity Value + Net Debt where Net Debt = SR,LR debt + min.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>ECON 205 Intermediate Microeconomics II</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/ECON-205-Intermediate-Microeconomics-II</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/ECON-205-Intermediate-Microeconomics-II</guid>
    <description>Background Knowledge § Monotonic Transformation Constrained Optimization Rational Taste Consumer Choice Theory § Utility Function Budget Constraints Utility Maximization Utility Maximization with Endowments Ordinary Demand Indirect Utility Function Expenditure Minimization Hicksian Demand Curve Expenditure Function &amp; See: Map of Microeconomic Optimization Theory of the Firm § Profit Maximization Input Demand and Output Supply Profit Function Cost Minimization Constrained Constrainted Input Demand Monopoly Equilibrium Theory § Microeconomic Market Equilibrium Trade between individuals Edgeworth Box Pareto Efficiency Compensating and Equivalent Variation Game Theory § Game Theory Dominant Strategy Equilibrium Equilibria in Game Theory Subgame Perfect Nash Equilibirum Repeated Game Oligopoly Games Bertrand Price Competition Cornout Quantity Competition .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econ 201 Intermediate Microeconomics I</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-201-Intermediate-Microeconomics-I</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-201-Intermediate-Microeconomics-I</guid>
    <description>Consumer Theory § Budget Lines Indifference Curve Constrained Optimization Income Effect (IE) Substitution Effect (SE) Types of Demand Curves (MicroEcon) Theory of the Firm § Production Function Profit Maximization Market Distortion § Price Controls International Trade Market Power § Game Theory Monopoly Bertrand Price Competition Monopolistic Competition Cartels and Collusion Public Good .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econ 204 Econometrics</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-204-Econometrics</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-204-Econometrics</guid>
    <description> Quote Correlation doesn’t imply Causation Econometrics Bivariate Ordinary Least Squares Regression Confidence Intervals and Hypothesis Testing in OLS Linear Regression Omitted Variables Multivariate Ordinary Least Squares Regression Homework 5.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econ 210 Macroeconomics</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-210-Macroeconomics</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-210-Macroeconomics</guid>
    <description> Macroeconomics Growth Rate Calculations GDP Agents of the Macro Economy Macroeconomic Market Equilibrium Laffer Curve Beveridge Curve Homogenous Degrees .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econ 361 Distributive Justice</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-361-Distributive-Justice</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-361-Distributive-Justice</guid>
    <description> Remember, there are still people starving as we speak. Applying Game Theory § Robert Axelrod - The Evolution of Cooperation Robert Frank - Passions within Reason J.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econ 371 Finance</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-371-Finance</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econ-371-Finance</guid>
    <description> Present Value Calculations Bonds (Finance) Equity Comparable Company (Comps) Analysis Portfolio Theory CAPM Model Futures Glossary Short-selling Trade-Through Interest Rate Derivatives (Finance) Contagion (Finance) .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Econometrics</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econometrics</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Econometrics</guid>
    <description> Establishing causality does “policy/behavior/program → outcome”? X→Y? Challenges Is it random noise? Removing outliers Are there exogenous factors? X is endogenous if X correlates with ϵ (error)—non-causal, lurking variable X is exogenous if X doesn’t correlation with ϵ—likely causal Regression Analysis: Yi​=β0​+β1​Xi​+ϵi​ β0​: intercept.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Economic Democracy</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Economic-Democracy</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Economic-Democracy</guid>
    <description> (Book) The Case for Economic Democracy (Economist) Andrew Cumbers (DevonThink) Economic Democracy and Labor Productivity .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 03:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>