<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>PK&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://pyoky.me/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on PK&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Algorithm</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Algorithm</guid>
    <description>Loose definition Note An algorithm… finishes in finite number of steps its answer is consistent it always gives the correct answer Algorithm Design Principles § Design What to compute How it computes what we want it to compute Correctness Why does it compute what we want it to compute Analysis &amp; Efficiency How much resources does it use? (Complexity) Most algorithms follow the following two standard models of computation Recursion Iteration Verifying Correctness § Warning There is no way to find out if an algorithm is correct.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Alienation</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Alienation</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Alienation</guid>
    <description>Commoditization of human labor § Trading labor Differences of age and sex have no longer any distinctive social validity for the working class. All are instruments of labour, more or less expensive to use, according to their age and sex.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Amartya Sen</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Amartya-Sen</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Amartya-Sen</guid>
    <description> Developer of the Human Development Index Author of (Article) Equality of What? Frequent interactions with Martha Nussbaum .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Anarcho-Syndicalism</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Anarcho-Syndicalism</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Anarcho-Syndicalism</guid>
    <description>Noam Chomsky Anarcho-: Decentralization of power Syndicalism: Worker’s union’s ownership of Means of Production A realistic alternative to Marxism .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Annuity</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Annuity</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Annuity</guid>
    <description>Annuities are… Money you borrowed: mortgages, etc. ⇒ pay regularly to pay off large amount Money you lent: social security credit, etc. ⇒ give large money, get regular payments later Amortization is the same thing but from a different perspective ⇒ You’re spreading a one-time cost into multiple years.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Approximating Distributions</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximating-Distributions</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximating-Distributions</guid>
    <description>thm. A Normal Distribution with μ=np,σ=np(1−p)​ will approximate a Binomial distribution with n trials and success probability p when np&gt;1 P(a≤X≤b)=k=a∑b​P(X=k)≃∫ab​fnormal​(μ=np,σ=np(1−p)​)dx REMARK.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Approximation Algorithm</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximation-Algorithm</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Approximation-Algorithm</guid>
    <description>def. Approximation Factor. α(n)-level approximation. For optimization problem π, ALG is a α-level optimization algorithm iff for input I of size n: max[OPT(I)ALG(I)​,ALG(I)OPT(I)​]=α(n) Smaller is better! Constant approximation factor: if approximation factor doesn’t depend on n, ALG is a constant α-level approximation .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Artificial Needs</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Artificial-Needs</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Artificial-Needs</guid>
    <description>Normally it’s human nature from which arises naturally the needs, and capital should be appropriated for Under the system of private property their significance is reversed.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Ascending Price Auction</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Ascending-Price-Auction</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Ascending-Price-Auction</guid>
    <description>Motivation. The VCG Auction is DSIC and Welfare-maximizing. But it’s also very complicated to explain to all agents. Instead, let’s think of a simpler, intuitive idea: ascending price auctions.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Assets (Finance)</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/Assets-(Finance)</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/Assets-(Finance)</guid>
    <description>Assets are anything that’s tradable. Equity Commodities Derivatives (Finance) Futures Real Estate Note A debt for one person is an asset for the lender.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>