<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>PK&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://pyoky.me/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on PK&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>&quot;Set&quot; Category</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/%22Set%22-Category</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/%22Set%22-Category</guid>
    <description>def. Set is a category where its objects are sets, and morphisms are standard functions. Consider the following objects: Empty set: Void. You can have morphism Absurd::Void→Int.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>&quot;Thin&quot; Category</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/%22Thin%22-Category</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/%22Thin%22-Category</guid>
    <description>Example. Consider the category where all morphisms are ≤. Not that these objects are numbers, but just that we can compare two elements. This is surprisingly a proper category.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Article) Equality of What?</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Equality-of-What-q</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Equality-of-What-q</guid>
    <description>(DevonThink) Sen,Equality Equity is about asking “what should be equal?” Libertarians: Equality of Rights Utilitarians: Equal Weighting of Utility Progressive Taxation: Equality of Need Satisfaction etc.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Article) Magic Ink - Information Software and the Graphical Interface</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Magic-Ink---Information-Software-and-the-Graphical-Interface</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Magic-Ink---Information-Software-and-the-Graphical-Interface</guid>
    <description>Notes on Magic Ink: Information Software and the Graphical Interface What You See is All You Get (WYSIAYG) UI design is: How information is presented: Graphic Design Personal accounting, Health app visualization How to manipulate and create: Industrial design Photoshop, Illustrator Users mostly want to learn something, not create something.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Blueprint) Nomura Traning</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Blueprint)-Nomura-Traning</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Blueprint)-Nomura-Traning</guid>
    <description>Success Criteria § Learn to be a productive software engineer Learn enough quant &amp; finance to understand fully the risk infra of Nomura Info § Finance § Financial Instruments Financial Institutions Credit Rating Role of Investment Banks Lifecycle of a Trade Credits Desk (Including Currency Carry Trade) Prime Client: institutional clients (hedge funds)ns Certificate of deposit Prime client Total return swap credit default swap insurance Money market funds quantitative easing Quantitative Risk Management § Probability Conditional Expectation for Stochastic Calculus Moment (Probability) Stochastic Process Quadratic Variation Stochastic Calculus Portfolio Theory (Risk) Basel Quantitative Risk Measurment Fair Value Accounting Risk-Neutral Assumption Market Risk Probabilistic/Statistical Models But what is a residual? Markov Chain Time Series Auto-Regressive &amp; Moving Average Statistical Inference Using ARMA Auto-Regressive &amp; Conditionally Heteroskedatic Data Engineering § Data Architecture Cloud Architecture Machine Learning § Technologies: Dask, Scikit Learn Cross Validation Hyperparameter Search Strategies Model Evaliation QQ Plot Permutation Feature Importance PDP &amp; ICE Plots Partial Dependence (PDPs) and Individual Conditional Expectation (ICE) Plots | Intuition and Math - YouTube LIME Spline functions Questions: a.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Godel, Escher, Bach</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-Godel-Escher-Bach</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-Godel-Escher-Bach</guid>
    <description>Winner of the Pulitzer Prize A metaphorical fugue on minds and machines in the spirit of Lewis Carroll Douglas Hofstadter's book is concerned directly with the nature of &quot;maps&quot; or links between formal systems.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Case for Economic Democracy</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-The-Case-for-Economic-Democracy</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-The-Case-for-Economic-Democracy</guid>
    <description>The idea that the people have a right to shape political decisions through democratic means is widely accepted. The same cannot be said of the decisions that impact on our everyday economic life in the workplace and beyond.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(HowTo) Cost Minimization</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(HowTo)-Cost-Minimization</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(HowTo)-Cost-Minimization</guid>
    <description>See also Profit Maximization Long Run Cost Minimization § minl,k​ C=wl+rk such that x=f(x) Lagrangian Optimization Optimal when Isoquant is tangent to the isocost Higher isoquant is not always better! it just means you’re producing more Warning Beware when MC is monotonically decreasing.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(LLL) Ethereum</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(LLL)-Ethereum</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(LLL)-Ethereum</guid>
    <description> (Paper) Eigenlayer - The Restaking Collective Layer 2 (Ethereum) Accounts. Two types: Externally Owned Account (EOA): public-private key pair. Your normal account, with address and a balance Contract Account.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(LLL) Nomura Traning</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(LLL)-Nomura-Traning</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(LLL)-Nomura-Traning</guid>
    <description>Finance § Security (Finance) Fixed Income: Bonds Equity Credit Rating Role of Investment Banks Lifecycle of a Trade Fixed Income Bonds: Govn’t (National/Municipal), Corporate Structured Products Emerging Market Debt Rates Desk Interest Rate Govn’t Bonds Bond futures Interest Rate Derivatives Credits Desk FX Interest Rate Swap (Including Currency Carry Trade) Prime Client: institutional clients (hedge funds)ns Certificate of deposit Forward Rate Agreement Prime client Total return swap credit default swap insurance Money market funds quantitative easing Quantitative Risk Management § Probability Conditional Expectation for Stochastic Calculus Moment (Probability) Stochastic Process Quadratic Variation Stochastic Calculus Portfolio Theory (Risk) Basel Quantitative Risk Measurment Fair Value Accounting Risk-Neutral Assumption Market Risk Probabilistic/Statistical Models But what is a residual? Markov Chain Time Series Auto-Regressive &amp; Moving Average Statistical Inference Using ARMA Auto-Regressive &amp; Conditionally Heteroskedatic Data Engineering § Data Architecture Cloud Architecture Machine Learning § Technologies: Dask, Scikit Learn Cross Validation Hyperparameter Search Strategies Model Evaliation QQ Plot Permutation Feature Importance PDP &amp; ICE Plots Partial Dependence (PDPs) and Individual Conditional Expectation (ICE) Plots | Intuition and Math - YouTube LIME Spline functions Questions: a.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>