<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>PK&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://pyoky.me/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on PK&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>(Article) Equality of What?</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Equality-of-What-q</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Equality-of-What-q</guid>
    <description>(DevonThink) Sen,Equality Equity is about asking “what should be equal?” Libertarians: Equality of Rights Utilitarians: Equal Weighting of Utility Progressive Taxation: Equality of Need Satisfaction etc.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Article) Magic Ink - Information Software and the Graphical Interface</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Magic-Ink---Information-Software-and-the-Graphical-Interface</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Article)-Magic-Ink---Information-Software-and-the-Graphical-Interface</guid>
    <description>Notes on Magic Ink: Information Software and the Graphical Interface What You See is All You Get (WYSIAYG) UI design is: How information is presented: Graphic Design Personal accounting, Health app visualization How to manipulate and create: Industrial design Photoshop, Illustrator Users mostly want to learn something, not create something.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Case for Economic Democracy</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-The-Case-for-Economic-Democracy</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Book)-The-Case-for-Economic-Democracy</guid>
    <description>The idea that the people have a right to shape political decisions through democratic means is widely accepted. The same cannot be said of the decisions that impact on our everyday economic life in the workplace and beyond.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(HowTo) Cost Minimization</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(HowTo)-Cost-Minimization</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(HowTo)-Cost-Minimization</guid>
    <description>See also Profit Maximization Long Run Cost Minimization § minl,k​ C=wl+rk such that x=f(x) Lagrangian Optimization Optimal when Isoquant is tangent to the isocost Higher isoquant is not always better! it just means you’re producing more Warning Beware when MC is monotonically decreasing.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Philosopher) Alexandre Kojeve</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Alexandre-Kojeve</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Alexandre-Kojeve</guid>
    <description> Alexandre Kojève (koh-ZHEV, French: [alɛksɑ̃dʁ kɔʒɛv]; 28 April 1902–4 June 1968) was a Russian-born French philosopher and statesman whose philosophical seminars had an immense influence on 20th-century French philosophy, particularly via his integration of Hegelian concepts into twentieth-century continental philosophy.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Philosopher) Edmund Husserl</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Edmund-Husserl</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Edmund-Husserl</guid>
    <description>See Phenomenology.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Philosopher) G. W. F. Hegel</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-G.-W.-F.-Hegel</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-G.-W.-F.-Hegel</guid>
    <description> Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel (; German: [ˈɡeːɔʁk ˈvɪlhɛlm ˈfʁiːdʁɪç ˈheːɡl̩]; 27 August 1770–14 November 1831) was a German philosopher and one of the most influential figures of German idealism and 19th-century philosophy.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>(Philosopher) Martin Heidegger</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Martin-Heidegger</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/(Philosopher)-Martin-Heidegger</guid>
    <description>See Phenomenology.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>10-09 Notes</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/10-09-Notes</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/10-09-Notes</guid>
    <description> Society’s Scripts of gender are grounded on biology but unfounded. Emergence of diverse modes of social interaction necessitate better ways of interaction Your Validating Emotions: your desire to be percieved as the cute girl, to perform that role (Gender is a performance) is built upon Your history in korea and japan your past relationships Optimistic Nihilism.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>581 Exam Topics</title>
    <link>https://pyoky.me/notes/581-Exam-Topics</link>
    <guid>https://pyoky.me/notes/581-Exam-Topics</guid>
    <description>Chapter 2: Time Value of Money § Simple vs compound interest From compound interest to continuous compounding Formulas for PV and FV of an annuity Amortization (payment towards interest and principal) PV and FV of Bonds Stock valuation (DDM) Chapter 3: Portfolio Theory § 2-securities: finding the global minimum variance portfolio using 1variable calculus Cases for ρ = 0, ρ = ±1 N-securities: finding the global minimum variance portfolio using Lagrange Understanding matrices V and H, quantities A, B, and C Chapter 4: Capital Market Theory § Understanding CML and SML lines Finding the sharp ratio and equation of the CML Deriving weight and risk-return of the Market Portfolio Deriving the formula for the Beta Chapter 5: Binomial Tree Models § Understanding the definition of a general binomial tree Deriving formulas for u_n, d_n, and p_n for the CRR tree From Binomial Tree to the Lognormal Model Chapter 6: Stochastic Calculus § Definition of SBM and GBM Intuition behind SBM: the symmetric random walk Properties of SBM in relation to the random walk Properties of the Lognormal Model for security prices Definition of the stochastic integral Using Ito’s formula in simple cases Chapter 7&amp;8: Derivatives and the BSM Model § Terminal payoff diagrams for Call and Put Put- []Call parity Binomial tree model for call options From Binomial tree model to the BSM formula Deriving the BSM PDE Understanding the BSM formula for Call and Put .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>